James Weisman

Cary, Illinois 847-828-6465 jamesweisman@comcast.net

Network & System Administrator, Manager and Trainer

Currently in the Web Design & Development program at McHenry County College. I have experienced in IT Management, System Administrator and Desktop Support. Experience training end user and computer support personal.

Information Technology Skills

- Web site design and management
- Windows (xp,7,8,10), Apple OS & iOS, Unix/Linux desktop
- Microsoft (Active Directory), Unix/Linux server
- Management of desktop support personal
- Purchasing of equipment and supplies
- Worked as part of a several management teams that built and setup new offices
- Telecommunication/Voicemail and Teleconferencing systems

Experience:

Currently in the Web Design & Development program at McHenry County College. I have also started freelancing in Web and Graphic design.

Glenbard High School District 87 District Technical Support Specialist Tier 2

2014 - 2016

- Supported administrators, staff and students
- Used Solar-winds trouble ticket system
- Supported Windows7 and Apple computers
- Supported iPads and other mobile devices
- Supported Microsoft Office 2010 & 2016
- Experience with trouble shooting, imaging, fixing of hardware, software and network problems.
- Web & Social Media Master for the Athletic booster club.

FOX VALLEY CAREER CENTER

201 3-2014

Kaneland Community Unit School District 302

Part-Time Instructor

 Taught classes in PC Maintenance, repair, networking, Web-Development, HTML and Cascading Style Sheets

COMPUTER SYSTEMS INSTITUTE

2011 - 2014

Part-Time Instructor

• Taught introduction to Computers, CompTIA A+ and CompTIA Net+ classes.

 Worked at Baxter Health Care as a computer consultant. I was a part of a team that migrated 500+ users to new computers at multiple locations across the country

COLLEGE OF LAKE COUNTY- Adjunct Professor/Web Master

2009 - 2010

 Taught a class for one semester called PC Operating Systems for A+ Certification. I had the added responsibility of being the Web Master for Adjunct Professor website

LAKE COUNTY TECHNOLOGY CAMPUS - Computer Teacher

2007-2009

Taught classes that covered hardware and operating systems (Windows, Linux and MAC)

FOX LAKE DISTRICT 114 - Technology Coordinator

2006-2007

- I was the District Technology Coordinator for District 115 in Fox Lake. I was responsible for the computers, servers and networks at two schools
- Improved the reliability of the District's backup and recovery system, proposed improvements to the school Norton Ghosting procedures, and improved security for the online storage of teacher and student data

Illinois State University, Normal Illinois

2003 - 2006

 I went back to school to obtain a Certification in Technology Education, with an endorsement in Computer Applications

MOTOROLA INC., - Manager/System Administrator

2000-2003

- I managed a staff of four Local Desktop Support Technicians
- I over saw the installation of a new network at a new off-site location
- I was in charge of the purchasing of computers
- Managed Microsoft & Unix Servers, printers, back-up systems, for two different divisions

Education & Training:

Illinois State University, Normal Illinois

- Certification in Technology Education Type 09 with an endorsement in Computer Applications Western Illinois University, Macomb, Illinois
- Bachelor of Science in Industrial Education and Technology

Computer Certifications:

- CompTIA A+ and CompTIA Net+ 005
- Microsoft Technology Associate: Networking, Windows Operating Systems, Server Administration, Security
- Apple Certified Associate Mac Integration

Volunteer Work

National Alliance on Mental Illness – McHenry County

• Word Press Web Master